International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, Aeronautical Industrial District Lodge 91 Records 1984.0017
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
- Series XI: Printed Material, 1937-1983
  - Subseries B: Flyers, undated, 1953-1982
    - Lodges
      - Broad Brook, 1954-1955 (Box 86:, Folder 2809)
      - Hamilton Standard, 1953-1957 (Box 86:, Folder 2810)
      - North Haven, 1953 (Box 86:, Folder 2811)
      - Sikorsky, 1956 (Box 86:, Folder 2812)
      - 1746, East Hartford, 1955-1960 (Box 86:, Folder 2813-2814)
      - Mixed lodges, ca. 1950s (Box 86:, Folder 2815)
      - Mixed lodges, ca. 1966 (Box 86:, Folder 2816-2817)
  - Subseries C: Publications, 1937-1983
    - AFL-CIO: strike information, 1974 (Box 87, Folder 2818)
    - "Impact of Military Spending on the Machinists Union", 1979 (Box 87, Folder 2819)
    - International Association of Machinists
      - Aircraft and Missile Conference, 1957-1959 (Box 87, Folder 2820)
      - California Metal Trades Association: agreement, 1963 (Box 87, Folder 2821)
      - Industrial Radio Lodge 1561 (MD): agreement, 1950 (Box 87, Folder 2822)
      - Technical Associates Lodge 1922 (Canada): agrmt., 1951 (Box 87, Folder 2823)
      - Republic Lodge 1987 (NY): agreement, 1962 (Box 87, Folder 2824)
    - International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers
      - General publications, undated (Box 87, Folder 2825)
      - Aerospace Update, 1977, 1981 (Box 87, Folder 2826)
      - Constitutions, 1958-1981 (Box 87, Folder 2827)
      - Constitution, Ladies Auxiliary, 1969 (Box 87, Folder 2828)
      - Convention, Grand Lodge, 27th, 1968 (Box 87, Folder 2829)
      - Convention, Grand Lodge, 29th, 1976 (Box 87, Folder 2830-2832)
      - Convention, Grand Lodge, 30th, 1980 (Box 87, Folder 2833)
      - Handbook for Members, undated (Box 87, Folder 2834)
      - Highlights of IAM History, ca. 1973 (Box 87, Folder 2835)
      - "How to..." Grand Lodge information packets, undated (Box 87, Folder 2836)
      - Keeping in Touch, 1974-1980 (Box 87, Folder 2837)
      - Jetlines, 1967-1971 (Box 87, Folder 2838)
      - The Machinist, 1961-1982 (Box 87-88:, Folder 2839-2856)
      - The Machinist special editions, undated (Box 88, Folder 2857)
      - New member kit, undated (Box 88, Folder 2858)
      - Official circulars, ca. 1944-1974 (Box 88, Folder 2859)
      - Rebuilding America Act, 1983 (Box 88, Folder 2860)
      - "Report from Headquarters", 1975-1981 (Box 88, Folder 2861-2864)
      - "Research Report", 1973-1980 (Box 88, Folder 2865)
      - Roster, 1974-1982 (Box 88, Folder 2866)
      - "Safety Gram", 1979, 1981 (Box 89, Folder 2867)
      - Strike policies and procedures, ca. 1978 (Box 89, Folder 2868)
    - Aeronautical Industrial District Lodge 91
      - New Union News, 1969-1975 (Box 89, Folder 2869)
      - Shoptalk, undated, 1976-1981 (Box 89, Folder 2870)
    - Aeronautical District Lodge 1578 (Santa Monica, CA): (Box 89, Folder 2871)
      - Missile-aire, 1969-1971
    - Machinists Non-Partisan League
      - General, undated (Box 89, Folder 2872)
      - Action, 1968-1977 (Box 89, Folder 2873-2878)
    - Pratt and Whitney: general, 1937, 1967 (Box 89, Folder 2879)
- Series XII: Photographs and Memorabilia, undated, 1974-1982
  - Subseries A: Photographs, undated, 1960-1982
    - Group photographs (unidentified), undated (Box 90)
    - Health care
      - Eye care program, undated
      - Food collection, undated
      - Health Clinic, undated
    - Historical Photographs
      - "Best of Hartford" (street scenes), undated
      - Historic prints and photos file, undated
      - Raymond Engineering, 1979 August 30
      - Weaving on a hand loom, undated
    - Individual photographs
      - Unidentified (2 envelopes), undated
      - Baker, Grace (Recording Secretary, D-91), undated
      - Guimond, Arthur (Secretary-Treasurer, GHLC), 1976 August
      - Guthrie, Woody, undated
      - Kiefer, Lou (Public Relations Officer), undated
      - Kuehnel, William (Recording Secretary, GHLC), 1976 April
      - Nash, Vincent and Diane, undated
      - Ostro, Justin (President, D-91), undated
      - Tracy, Charles (Business Representative, D-91), undated
      - Wimpinsinger, William (visit to E. Hartford, CT), 1981
    - Meetings and Conferences
      - IAM Conference on Civil Rights, 25th anniversary, Hartford, CT, undated
      - Mass meetings (Unidentified), undated
      - Unidentified, undated
    - Press
      - Award presentations, undated
      - New Union News membership drive, 1977
      - Press conferences, undated
      - Shop Talk, undated
    - Protests and Demonstrations
      - Bottle Bill Protest, 1974
      - Local meeting action 1746, undated
      - Nuclear Freeze Rally, NYC, 1982 June
      - AFL-CIO Solidarity Day, Washington, D.C., 1981 September 19
      - IAM-UAW "Solidarity 74", 1974
      - Social Activities (Various), undated
    - Steward Issues
      - Shop Stewards, 1974
      - Stewards class: Local 1746, undated
      - Stewards protest (Shoptalk photos), 1981 December 8
    - Strikes
      - Canadian strike story, undated
      - June 1960 strike
      - Other strike photographs, undated
      - Red Cross nurses strike, undated
      - Stagehand strike, Bushnell Theater, Hartford, CT, undated
    - Union leadership
      - Union leaders—Purcell, Dye, Nellis and Crafa, 1978 March
      - Individual photographs (unidentified, 2 folders), undated
    - Unidentified photos, proofs and negatives
      - Negatives (5 folders), undated
      - Photographs, 1974-1977
      - Photo-proofs, undated
  - Subseries B: Memorabilia, undated, 1968-1974
    - Buttons and badges, undated (Box 91)
    - General, undated
    - Album: "A message for you from Justin Ostro", 1968 November 30
    - Stickers, 1974
- Series XIII: Microfilm and Tape Recordings, undated, 1953-1967
  - Subseries A: Microfilm, undated, 1964-1967
    - NLRB 1-CA-3355 case, 1965 (Box 92, Othertype 1-10)
    - "Exhibits" 1-CA-3355, undated; (3 rolls) (Box 92, Othertype Unnumbered)
    - Case 9084-9085, 1965 March (Box 92, Othertype A-B)
    - Pratt and Whitney Aircraft Book, 1965 April 7 (Box 92, Othertype 1)
    - Pratt and Whitney Records, 1964 Fall (Box 92, Othertype 1x, 3x, 4x, 5x)
    - Hamilton Standard Termination records, 1964 Fall (Box 92, Othertype CX)
    - Local records, undated (Box 92, Othertype 1(35), 2 (35), 3 (35))
    - "Wells Emp. Complement" Pre-trial information, 1967 February (Box 92, Othertype Unnumbered)
    - Canel: Bartolotta to Marshall, undated (Box 92, Othertype 1)
    - Pratt and Whitney Hourly Employee Classification Records
      - Howland (#221) - Hunter (#14762) (Box 92, Othertype P&W 1)
      - Bryder (#13790) - Miron (#71150) (Box 92, Othertype P&W 2)
      - Serafin (#71258) - Guhl (#104860) (Box 92, Othertype P&W 3)
      - Bard (#104877) - Brown (#64521) (Box 92, Othertype P&W 4)
      - Culver (#64540) - Wilchinski (#77647) (Box 92, Othertype P&W 5)
      - Fortuna (#77765) - Truesdal (#78589) (Box 92, Othertype P&W 6)
      - Del Mastro (#78716) - Peterson (#81259) (Box 92, Othertype P&W 7)
      - Hemmann (#89000) - Metcalf (#102242) (Box 92, Othertype P&W 8)
      - Satagaj (#102252) - Martin (#85802) (Box 92, Othertype P&W 9)
      - Pschicholtz (#85829) - Strong (#22286) (Box 92, Othertype P&W 10)
      - Gilberson, Frank (#22597) - Kearney (#168168) (Box 92, Othertype P&W 11)
    - Southington
      - Macey (#167182) - DeLuco (#64819) (Box 92, Othertype P&W Southington)
      - Burns (#64838) (Box 92, Othertype P&W Southington)
  - Subseries B: Tape Recordings, undated, 1953-1964
    - Spirit of 1746 - IAUM -D-91, [] October 18
    - Spirit of 1746 - IAUM -D-91, [] October 25
    - Spirit of 1746 - IAUM -D-91, [] November 1
    - IAM #4, 1953 November 8
    - IAM #5, 1953 November 14
    - "Al Hayes" --Bushnell Hall, [] November 22
    - IAM Strike—State Theater, 1st shift meeting, [] December 9
    - IAM Strike—State Theater, 2nd shift meeting, [] December 9
    - IAM, 1953 December 6
    - IAM, 1953 December 13
    - IAM, 1954 January 10
    - IAM, 1954 January 17
    - Contract Explanation, 1954 March 21
    - Contract (Lawyer), 1954 March 21
    - Contract Speech (Legal), 1954 March 21
    - 3 unidentified reels, undated
    - "World of Labor" President Johnson, Gordon Cole, Dean Ruth and Jane Stolas, 1964 May 11